Thompson, S. mss., LMC 2421
Lilly Library
Thompson, S. mss.
1911-1976
Lilly Library
Thompson, Stith, 1885-
LMC 2421
22.25 linear feet 13 boxes, 3 oversize
Thompson, S. mss., 1911-1976, consists of the papers of Stith Thompson, 1885-1976, including correspondence; writings by Thompson; biographical and autobiographical materials such as travel files and diaries; materials relating to professional societies and conferences to which he belonged and attended; and family genealogies on which he worked over the years.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Acquisition Information
Gift. 1972, 1977, 2003.
Biographical Note
Stith Thompson, 1885-1976, was an American folklorist and the compiler of the Motif-Index of Folk Literature (published 1935, revised 1957). He was a professor of English and Folklore at Indiana University and was instrumental, along with his colleague Richard Dorson, in Folkore becoming an academic department at Indiana University.
Thompson was born in Bloomfield, Kentucky. He attended Butler University in Indianapolis before receiving his BA from the University of Wisconsin in 1909. He received his master's in English literature from the University of California, Berkeley in 1912 and his doctorate from Harvard. He joined the IU faculty in 1921.
Beginning in 1942, Thompson organized summer Folklore Institutes at Indiana University which lasted beyond his retirement from tenure in 1955. In 1962, a permanent Institute of Folklore was established at Bloomington with Richard Dorson as administrator.
Scope and Content Note
Collection consists of the papers of Stith Thompson, 1885-1976, including correspondence; writings by Thompson; biographical and autobiographical materials such as travel files and diaries; materials relating to professional societies and conferences to which he belonged and attended; and family genealogies on which he worked over the years.
Manuscripts index in the Lilly Library includes entries at the item level.
Arrangement/Organization
Collection is organized in seven series: I. Correspondence, II. Writings, III. Biographical Materials, IV. Societies and Conferences, V. Genealogies, VI. Printed Materials, and VII Additions.
Related Materials
Several collections related to the Folklore Institute are held at the University Archives, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana.
Folklore; Folklorists --Correspondence.; Indiana University; Indiana University -- Faculty; Indiana University. Folklore Institute; Indiana University; Thompson, Stith, 1885- --Correspondence.; Thompson family.; Beauchamp family.; McCloskey family.; Lincoln family.; Mitchell family.; Pipes family.; Shipley family.
- Correspondence, 1913-1972
  Scope and Contents
  The Correspondence series is arranged chronologically as well as alphabetically.
  - Chronological, 1913-1972 (Box 1)
  - A (Box 2)
    - Albrect, William, 1957-1963 (Box 2)
    - Allen, Robert E. B., 1943-1944 (Box 2)
    - Altrocchi, Rudolph, 1919-1939 (Box 2)
    - Amades, Sr. Joan, 1953-1959 (Box 2)
    - Anderson, Walter, 1929-1962 (Box 2)
    - Andersson, Otto, 1950-1968 (Box 2)
    - Arlt, Gustave A., 1935-1941 (Box 2)
    - Aronco, Gianfranco d', 1950-1968 (Box 2)
  - B (Box 2)
    - Balys, Joans, 1946-1956 (Box 2)
    - Bartók, Bela, 1941-1971 (Box 2)
    - Barua, B. K., 1948-1953 (Box 2)
    - Baughman, Ernest W., 1948-1968 (Box 2)
    - Baum, Paull F., 1949 (Box 2)
    - Bayard, Samuel P., 1948-1957 (Box 2)
    - Beatty, Arthur, 1911-1947 (Box 2)
    - Beckwith, Martha, 1928-1955 (Box 2)
    - Berze Nagy, Janos, 1961 (Box 2)
    - Boatright, Mody, 1956 (Box 2)
    - Boberg, Inger, 1945-1960 (Box 2)
    - Bodker, Laurits, 1946-1960 (Box 2)
    - Boggs, Ralph S., 1927-1955 (Box 2)
    - Boratav, Pertev N., 1948-1952 (Box 2)
    - Botkin, B. A., 1929-1938 (Box 2)
    - Bowen, Ray P., 1921-1941 (Box 2)
    - Brewer, J. Mason, 1936-1949 (Box 2)
    - Brewster, Paul G., 1935-1951 (Box 2)
    - Briggs, Katharine, 1959 (Box 2)
    - Brown, A. C. L., 1917-1945 (Box 2)
    - Brown, Carleton, 1939 (Box 2)
  - C (Box 2)
    - Campbell, Ake, 1936-1950 (Box 2)
    - Campbell, John Lorne, 1947-1968 (Box 2)
    - Campbell, Marie Alice, 1952-1968 (Box 2)
    - Carter, H. H., 1924-1940 (Box 2)
    - Cascudo, Luis da Camara, 1942-1956 (Box 2)
    - Chase, Richard, 1938-1945 (Box 2)
    - Christiansen, Reidar Th., 1927-1958 (Box 2)
    - Clarke, Kenneth, 1956-1965 (Box 2)
    - Claudel, Alice, 1942-1959 (Box 2)
    - Coffin, Tristram, 1930-1953 (Box 2)
    - Cortazar, Augusto Raúl, 1941-1968 (Box 2)
    - Creighton, Helen, 1937-1959 (Box 2)
    - Cross, Tom Peete, 1934-1952 (Box 2)
    - Crowell, Robert L., 1944-1948 (Box 2)
  - D (Box 2)
    - Davidson, Levette, 1938-1954 (Box 2)
    - Davis, Harold, 1939-1945 (Box 2)
    - Dawkins, Richard M., 1947-1954 (Box 2)
    - Delarue, Paul, 1945-1957 (Box 2)
    - Dobie, J. Frank, 1951-1954 (Box 2)
    - Dorson, Richard, 1944-1966 (Box 2)
    - DuPouy, Walter, 1947-1953 (Box 2)
    - Dundes, Alan, 1964-1965 (Box 2)
  - E (Box 3)
    - Eberhard, Wolfram, 1949-1961 (Box 3)
    - Eliason, Norman E., 1937-1945 (Box 3)
    - Ellis, Milton, 1917-1942 (Box 3)
    - Elwin, Verrier, 1949-1959 (Box 3)
    - Emeneau, Murray B., 1939-1961 (Box 3)
    - Emrich, Duncan, 1946-1951 (Box 3)
    - Encyclopaedia Britannica (Box 3)
    - Erixon, Sigurd, 1937-1959 (Box 3)
    - Eskeröd, Albert, 1953-1954 (Box 3)
    - Espinosa, Aurelio, 1933-1959 (Box 3)
  - F (Box 3)
    - Fansler, Dean S., 1930-1952 (Box 3)
    - Fejos, Paul, 1949-1960 (Box 3)
    - Felice, A. de, 1968 (Box 3)
    - Fenton, William N., 1960-1963 (Box 3)
    - Fife, Austin, 1942-1958 (Box 3)
    - Filson Club, 1959-1961 (Box 3)
    - Flowers, Helen L., 1948-1955 (Box 3)
    - Frick, Constance, 1939-1943 (Box 3)
    - Friederich, Werner P., 1945-1958 (Box 3)
    - Fulbright Act, 1948-1953 (Box 3)
  - G (Box 3)
    - Gardner, Emelyn E., 1934-1942 (Box 3)
    - Gassner, John, 1941-1953 (Box 3)
    - Gaster, Theodor H., 1946-1953 (Box 3)
    - Gayton, Ann H., 1935-1950 (Box 3)
    - Gerould, Gordon H., 1935-1947 (Box 3)
    - Gillmor, Frances, 1943-1967 (Box 3)
    - Goodwyn, Frank, 1943-1951 (Box 3)
    - Gorrell, Robert M., 1948-1958 (Box 3)
    - Goswami, P., 1952-1964 (Box 3)
    - Grafenauer, Ivan, 1958-1959 (Box 3)
    - Graham, D. C., 1951-1961 (Box 3)
    - Grebanier, Bernard D. N., 1938-1942 (Box 3)
    - Greenway, John, 1953-1957 (Box 3)
    - Greever, Garland, 1916-1936 (Box 3)
    - Guggenheim Fellowship (Box 3)
    - Gunda, Bela, 1945-1947 (Box 3)
  - H (Box 3)
    - Haavio, Martii, 1950-1957 (Box 3)
    - Hagler, Margaret, 1964 (Box 3)
    - Halpert, Herbert, 1939-1955 (Box 3)
    - Hammerich, L. L., 1949-1958 (Box 3)
    - Hand, Wayland D., 1941-1971 (Box 3)
    - Harris, Robert E. G., 1926-1959 (Box 3)
    - Hassell, J. W., Jr., 1941-1961 (Box 3)
    - Haywood, Charles, 1948-1952 (Box 3)
    - Heilfurth, Gerhard, 1970 (Box 3)
    - Henssen, Gottfried, 1938-1946 (Box 3)
    - Herold, Ludwig, 1938 (Box 3)
    - Herskovits, Melville J., 1935-1945 (Box 3)
    - Herzog, George, 1935-1955 (Box 3)
    - Hinton, James, 1923-1925 (Box 3)
    - Howe, Will D., 1928-1946 (Box 3)
    - Hustvedt, Sigurd B., 1928-1936 (Box 3)
    - Hymes, Dell, 1960-1961 (Box 3)
  - I (Box 3)
    - Ikeda, Hiroko, 1950-1967 (Box 3)
    - Irwin, Constance H. (Box 3)
      General
      (see Frick, Constance)
  - J (Box 3)
    - Jackson, George Pullen, 1945-1947 (Box 3)
    - Jackson, Kenneth, 1938-1946 (Box 3)
    - Jacobs, Melville, 1961-1962 (Box 3)
    - Jagendorf, Moritz, 1949-1953 (Box 3)
    - Jakobson, Roman and Svatava, 1948-1950 (Box 3)
    - James, Thelma, 1929-1953 (Box 3)
    - Jansen, William H., 1941-1959 (Box 3)
    - Jente, Richard, 1931-1946 (Box 3)
    - Johnson, Aili K., 1946-1958 (Box 3)
    - Jones, Louis C., 1943-1954 (Box 3)
  - K (Box 4)
    - Kamen-Kaye, Dorothy, 1949-1954 (Box 4)
    - Karpeles, Maud, 1950-1956 (Box 4)
    - Keller, John E., 1946-1963 (Box 4)
    - Kiefer, Emma E., 1937-1938 (Box 4)
    - Kirkland, Edwin C., 1933-1958 (Box 4)
    - Kirtley, Bacil, 1953-1959 (Box 4)
    - Klipple, May A., 1934-1955 (Box 4)
    - Knopf, Alfred A., 1953-1956 (Box 4)
    - Koch, Bill, 1954-1962 (Box 4)
    - Köngäs, E. K., 1958-1961 (Box 4)
    - Krader, Barbara, 1950-1968 (Box 4)
    - Kroeber, A. L., 1941-1959 (Box 4)
    - Krohn, Väinö, 1925-1937 (Box 4)
  - L (Box 4)
    - Lacourciére, Luc, 1946-1958 (Box 4)
    - Laird, Charlton G., 1943-1956 (Box 4)
    - Lange, Francisco Curt, 1948-1953 (Box 4)
    - Law, Robert A., 1933 (Box 4)
    - Laya, J. C., 1939-1951 (Box 4)
    - Laytano, Dante de, 1944-1958 (Box 4)
    - Leach, MacEdward, 1943-1962 (Box 4)
    - Lee, Hector, 1944-1965 (Box 4)
    - Lessa, William, 1952-1963 (Box 4)
    - Levin, Isidor, 1965-1967 (Box 4)
    - Lewis, Elaine, 1934-1946 (Box 4)
    - Leyen, Friedrich von der, 1952 (Box 4)
    - Lid, Nils, 1946-1957 (Box 4)
    - Liljeblad, Sven, 1936-1971 (Box 4)
    - Lillard, Richard, 1947-1958 (Box 4)
    - Lindgren, E. J., 1937-1958 (Box 4)
    - Liscano, Juan, 1947-1948 (Box 4)
    - Liungman, Waldemar, 1951-1954 (Box 4)
    - Lomax, Alan, 1937-1951 (Box 4)
    - Lo Nigro, Sebastian, 1957-1959 (Box 4)
    - Loorits, Oskar, 1945-1953 (Box 4)
    - Lord, Albert B., 1950-1954 (Box 4)
    - Luomala, Katharine, 1936-1959 (Box 4)
    - Lüthi, Max, 1961 (Box 4)
  - M (Box 4)
    - MacClintock, L., 1948 (Box 4)
    - McDermott, John Francis, 1953-1957 (Box 4)
    - McHugh, Roger, 1948 (Box 4)
    - McIntosh, Angus, 1949-1956 (Box 4)
    - McKay, J. G., 1936-1940 (Box 4)
    - McKinlay, Arthur, 1937-1953 (Box 4)
    - Malone, Kempe, 1932-1933 (Box 4)
    - Marie Ursule, Sister, 1949-1950 (Box 4)
    - Marjerrison, Mary, 1927-1935 (Box 4)
    - Marshall, Alexander H., 1943-1953 (Box 4)
    - Maticetov, Milko, 1959-1961 (Box 4)
    - Maurer, David W., 1939-1945 (Box 4)
    - Mayer, Fannie Hagin, 1952-1955 (Box 4)
    - Megas, Georgios, 1957-1971 (Box 4)
    - Melo, Verisimmo de, 1948-1955 (Box 4)
    - Mendoza, Virginia de, 1941-1955 (Box 4)
    - Meyer, Robert T., 1945-1954 (Box 4)
    - Meyncke, Gretchen D., 1938 (Box 4)
    - Millican, C. E., 1926-1938 (Box 4)
    - Mitcham, Mildred, 1947-1953 (Box 4)
    - Mitchell, Ruth, 1944-1960 (Box 4)
    - Moder, Frances, 1925-1926 (Box 4)
    - Montgomery, Margaret, 1935-1953 (Box 4)
    - Morris, Alton C., 1936-1946 (Box 4)
    - Musick, Ruth Ann, 1945-1967 (Box 4)
  - N (Box 4)
    - Nett, Bruno, 1952-1956 (Box 4)
    - Newman, Soledad, 1959-1961 (Box 4)
      (see also Perez)
    - Niles, John Jacob, 1939-1948 (Box 4)
    - Nipp, Francis S., 1939-1943 (Box 4)
    - Noe, Cotton, 1934-1952 (Box 4)
    - Nostrand, Howard L., 1965 (Box 4)
    - Noy, Dov, 1955-1971 (Box 4)
    - Noyes, Russell, 1929-1950 (Box 4)
  - O (Box 4)
    - O'Duilearga, Séamus, 1935-1959 (Box 4)
    - Olivares, Figueroa R., 1948-1952 (Box 4)
    - Ong, Walter, S. J. (Box 4)
    - Orrick, Allan H., 1958-1966 (Box 4)
    - Ortutay, Gyula, 1945-1947 (Box 4)
    - O'Suilleabhain, Sean, 1937-1964 (Box 4)
    - Owens, Alice Bess, 1939-1942 (Box 4)
  - P (Box 4)
    - Pasquali, P. S., 1937-1939 (Box 4)
    - Patch, H. R., 1950 (Box 4)
    - Patton, Edwina, 1934-1938 (Box 4)
    - Pawlowska, Harriet, 1941-1946 (Box 4)
    - Payne, Fernandus, 1937-1945 (Box 4)
    - Payne, L. W., 1923-1929 (Box 4)
    - Pearce, T. M., 1944-1958 (Box 4)
    - Peate, Iowerth, 1937 (Box 4)
    - Peeters, K. C., 1966 (Box 4)
    - Penzer, N. M., 1930-1952 (Box 4)
    - Pereira Salas, Eugenio, 1945-1951 (Box 4)
    - Perez, Soledad, 1962 (Box 4)
    - Perry, Ben, 1941-1959 (Box 4)
    - Pfaender, Lucile, 1932-1935 (Box 4)
    - Pinckney, Sarah, 1948-1953 (Box 4)
    - Pino Saavedra, Yolando, 1947-1962 (Box 4)
    - Pires de Lima, F., 1959-1965 (Box 4)
    - Pop, Mihai, 1965 (Box 4)
    - Pound, Louise, 1926-1940 (Box 4)
  - R (Box 4)
    - Raben, Joe, 1947-1954 (Box 4)
    - Radin, Paul, 1930 (Box 4)
    - Rael, Juan B., 1930-1957 (Box 4)
    - Randolph, Vance, 1952-1956 (Box 4)
    - Ranke, Kurt, 1949-1965 (Box 4)
    - Rath, Moser, 1951-1953 (Box 4)
    - Reinhard, J. R., 1930-1942 (Box 5)
    - Richmond, Edson, 1949-1957 (Box 5)
    - Ridenour, Harry, 1937-1957 (Box 5)
    - Roberts, Elizabeth, 1932-1956 (Box 5)
    - Roberts, Leonard, 1949-1955 (Box 5)
    - Roberts, Warren, 1948-1960 (Box 5)
    - Robinson, F. N., 1933-1955 (Box 5)
    - Röhrich, Lutz, 1956-1960 (Box 5)
    - Rooth, A., 1952-1971 (Box 5)
    - Rose, Harold, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - Rotunda, D. P., 1936-1948 (Box 5)
    - Ruben, Walter, 1946-1947 (Box 5)
    - Rubin, Ruth, 1954-1955 (Box 5)
  - S (Box 5)
    - Sanderson, S., 1953-1956 (Box 5)
    - Sapir, Edward, 1929-1937 (Box 5)
    - Sarton, George, 1947-1950 (Box 5)
    - Sayers, Frances Clarke, 1937-1942 (Box 5)
    - Schacht, P. L., 1927-1940 (Box 5)
    - Schlauch, Margaret, 1932-1944 (Box 5)
    - Schmidt, Leopold, 1953 (Box 5)
    - Schwartzbaum, Haim, 1952-1958 (Box 5)
    - Sebeok, T. A., 1949-1954 (Box 5)
    - Seeger, Charles, 1946-1951 (Box 5)
    - Sen, Gopi Nath, 1949-1952 (Box 5)
    - Simpson, Helen Hartikka, 1950-1956 (Box 5)
    - Smith, Reed, 1925-1939 (Box 5)
    - Spargo, John W., 1927-1946 (Box 5)
    - Spivey, Herman E., 1948-1951 (Box 5)
    - Stegemeier, Henri, 1948-1951 (Box 5)
    - Strömbäck, Dag, 1939 (Box 5)
    - Stutsman, Grace M., 1951-1952 (Box 5)
    - Swahn, D. J., 1956-1958 (Box 5)
    - Sydow, Wilhelm von, 1929-1947 (Box 5)
    - Sweeny, Margaret, 1934-1948 (Box 5)
  - T (Box 5)
    - Tabor, John, 1916-1947 (Box 5)
    - Tanner, William M., 1917-1918 (Box 5)
    - Tatlock, J. S. P., 1943 (Box 5)
    - Taylor, Archer, 1916-1970; (5 folders) (Box 5)
    - Thomas, Nora, 1930-1935 (Box 5)
    - Thompson, Harold W., 1932-1954 (Box 5)
    - Thompson, Kate A., 1923-1941 (Box 5)
    - Thompson, William L., 1916-1951 (Box 5)
    - Tillhagen, C. H., 1946-1952 (Box 5)
    - Toschi, Paolo, 1950-1959 (Box 5)
    - Tower, Roy A., 1943-1953 (Box 5)
    - Tyler, George, 1932-1935 (Box 5)
  - U (Box 5)
    - U. S. Information Agency, 1954-1955 (Box 5)
    - Upadhyaya, H. S., 1968-1969 (Box 5)
    - Upadhyaya, K. D., 1954-1966 (Box 5)
    - Utley, Francis Lee, 1939-1971 (Box 5)
  - V (Box 5)
    - Valente, Phyllis P., 1952-1955 (Box 5)
    - Van Gennep, Arnold, 1938 (Box 5)
    - Varagnac, Andre, 1947-1950 (Box 5)
    - Vega, Carlos, 1953-1958 (Box 5)
    - Vilkuna, K., 1938-1940 (Box 5)
    - Voegelin, Carl, 1931-1955 (Box 5)
    - Vries, Jane de, 1927-1953 (Box 5)
  - W (Box 5)
    - Wallace, Roy, 1937-1942 (Box 5)
    - Wallis, Wilaon, 1943-1958 (Box 5)
    - Walton, Ivan, 1938 (Box 5)
    - Wang, Arthur, 1944-1952 (Box 5)
    - Warren, Charles, 1949-1950 (Box 5)
    - Warren, Robert Penn, 1950 (Box 5)
    - Waterman, Richard A., 1948-1950 (Box 5)
    - Watt, J. A., 1917-1939 (Box 5)
    - Wellek, René, 1950 (Box 5)
    - Wells, Herman B, 1938-1968 (Box 5)
    - Weltfish, Gene, 1937-1940 (Box 5)
    - Wenner-Gren Foundation, 1954 (Box 5)
    - Wesselksi, Albert, 1931-1939 (Box 5)
    - White, Newman I., 1943-1948 (Box 5)
    - Wikelund, Phil, 1952-1955 (Box 5)
    - Wildhaber, Robert, 1957-1968 (Box 5)
    - Wilson, George P., 1944-1950 (Box 5)
    - Wilson, Gordon, 1929-1950 (Box 5)
    - Winger, Bjorn, 1928-1937 (Box 5)
    - Winther, O. O., 1945-1950 (Box 5)
    - Work, James A., 1951-1953 (Box 5)
    - Wright, Louis B., 1946-1958 (Box 5)
    - Wycoco-Moore, R., 1950-1957 (Box 5)
  - X-Z (Box 5)
    - Young, Clarence, 1937-1941 (Box 5)
    - Zucker, A. E., 1938-1944 (Box 5)
- Writings
  - Books
    - British Poets of the Nineteenth Century (Box 6)
      Publicity and reviews
    - English Literature and its Backgrounds (Box 6)
    - Folklorist's Progress (Box 6)
      Text; publicity and reviews
      See also Oversize for bound copy
    - The Folktale (Box 6)
      Production materials; publicity and reviews
    - Four Symposia on Folklore (Box 6)
    - Motif-Index of Folk-literature (Box 6)
      Corrections; publicity and reviews
    - The New Handbook of English (Box 6)
    - One Hundred Favorite Folktales (Box 6)
    - Our Heritage of World Literature (Box 6)
      Revision; production materials; publicity and reviews
    - The Pentamerone of Basile (Box 6)
    - Regional American folklore, 1944-1950 (Box 6)
      Correspondence, 1944-1950
    - Tales of North American Indians (Box 6)
    - The Types of the Folktale (FFC 184), 1959-1971 (Box 6)
      Revision; correspondence 1959-1971
    - Book proposals (Box 6)
  - Articles
    - American Folklore (Box 6)
    - Folk Literature (Box 6)
    - Folklore (Box 6)
    - Folklore (Box 6)
      (New Catholic Encyclopedia)
    - Folklore and Religion (Box 6)
    - Folktale Typology and the Pacific Area (Box 6)
    - Folktales and Legends (Box 6)
    - Foreword (Box 6)
    - Greeting to Indiana Folklore (Box 6)
    - Hypothetical Forms in Folktale Study (Box 6)
    - Mythology (Box 6)
      (Grolier Society)
    - Mythology (Box 6)
      (Oxford Encyclopedia)
    - La Organinazion Internacional de Investigaciones Folkloricas (Box 6)
    - Rituals (Box 6)
    - Variety in American Folk Tradition (Box 6)
  - Schoolwork (Box 6)
  - Reviews (Box 6)
  - Lectures
    - Colloquium on the folktale (Box 6)
    - English department in the twenties (Box 6)
    - Folklore of the Americas: An opportunity and a challenge (Box 6)
    - A humanist's creed (Box 6)
    - Introducing folklore (Box 6)
    - The modern study of the folktale (Box 6)
    - 100 favorite folktales (Box 6)
    - South American tour (Box 6)
      (10 lectures)
    - Story-telling to story-writing (Box 6)
    - The typology of folklore (Box 6)
    - Varying strains of American folklore (Box 6)
    - Untitled (Box 6)
    - Announcements, 1939-1969 (Box 6)
  - Writings by Others
    - Studies in folklore in honor of distinguished service (Box 6)
      Professor Stith Thompson
      Publicity and Reviews
    - Bibliographies (Box 6)
    - Publicity and reviews, miscellaneous (Box 6)
- Biographical Materials
  - Vitae, research reports, bibliographies (Box 7)
  - Commencement programs (Box 7)
    (Grad school--graduate; honorary degrees)
  - Memorial services programs (Box 7)
  - Appointment papers, (1912-1968) (Box 7)
  - Contracts, (1916-1944) (Box 7)
  - Honors (Box 7)
    - Certificates and citations (Box 7)
    - 70th birthday celebration (Box 7)
    - Name in print (Box 7)
    - Articles about S. Thompson (Box 7)
  - Travels (Box 7)
    - Correspondence, 1913-1965 (Box 7)
    - Travel diaries: (Box 7)
      - Europe, 1937 (Box 7)
      - South America, 1947 (Box 7)
      - Scandinavia, 1951-1952 (Box 7)
        See also Oversize
      - Iceland, Denmark, Holland, 1955 (Box 7)
      - Europe, 1956-1957 (Box 7)
      - South America, 1960-1961 (Box 7)
      - Belgium, Holland, France, Italy, 1962 (Box 7)
      - Greece, 1964 (Box 7)
      - Europe, 1969 (Box 7)
    - Itineraries (Box 7)
    - Photographs: (Box 7)
      - Bolivia, 1947 (Box 7)
      - Brazil, 1947 (Box 7)
      - Venezuela, 1947 (Box 7)
      - misc., 1947 (Box 7)
  - Friends of Stith Thompson (Box 7)
  - Awards and portrait of Archer Taylor (Ovflat 21)
- Societies and Conferences
  - Societies
    - American Folklore Society (Box 7)
    - American Philosophical Society (Box 7)
    - Comissao Nacional de Folclore (Box 7)
    - Commission Internationale des Artes et Traditions Populaires (C.I.A.P.) (Box 7)
    - Hoosier Folklore Society (Box 7)
    - Instituto Nacional de Antropologia (Box 7)
    - International Society for Folk Narrative Research (Box 7)
    - MLA Committee on Folktales (Box 8)
    - New Mexico Folklore Society (Box 8)
    - Societe Internationale d'Ethnologie et de Folklore (Box 8)
      (Successor to C.I.A.P.)
    - Texas Folklore Society (Box 8)
  - Conferences
    - All India folk-culture conference (Box 8)
    - American scientific congress (Box 8)
    - American-Yugoslav folklore seminar (Box 8)
    - Asian folklore conference (Box 8)
    - Commission Internationale des Artes et Traditions Populaires (Box 8)
    - Conference on the character and state of studies in folklore (Box 8)
    - Congress for science of folktales (Box 8)
    - Congress of the international comparative literature association (Box 8)
    - Congresso Brasileiro de folclore (Box 8)
    - Deutscher volkskunde-kongress (Box 8)
    - European conference on folklore (Box 8)
    - Folklore and fiction in the far west (Box 8)
    - Hoosier Folklore Society (Box 8)
    - International congress for European ethnology (Box 8)
    - International congress of anthropological and ethnological sciences (Box 8)
    - International congress of ethnography (Box 8)
    - International congress of folklore (Box 8)
    - International folk music conference (Box 8)
    - International Musicological Society (Box 8)
    - International Society for Folk Narrative Research (Box 8)
    - Internationales kongress der volkserzahlungsforschen (Box 8)
    - Kansas Folklore Society (Box 8)
    - Kentucky Folklore Society (Box 8)
    - Minority groups in the far west--their music and folklore (Box 8)
    - Nebraska Folklore Society (Box 8)
    - Nordiske folkelivs -og folkeminneforskarmote (Box 8)
    - Pacific science conference (Box 8)
    - Societe Internationale d'Ethnologie et de Folklore (Box 8)
    - Summer conference on Latin American folklore (Box 8)
    - Texas Folklore Society (Box 8)
    - Western folklore conference (Box 8)
    - World congress of Jewish studies (Box 8)
  - Folk Festivals (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Addresses (Box 8)
    - Clippings (Box 8)
    - Fieldwork (Box 8)
    - Folklore programs--IU (Box 8)
    - Folklore programs other than IU (Box 8)
    - Freshman English (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 8)
- Genealogy
  - Beauchamp family (Box 8)
    - Correspondence (Box 8)
      - 1901-1949 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - , n.d., 1950-1971 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Beauchamps in England, before 1630 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Costin Beauchamp, his brothers and descendants. (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Edmund Beauchamp of Maryland and descendants to Costin (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - for possible additions to Beauchamp genealogy (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Bodine family (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Hobart family (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Lincoln family (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, n.d., 1927-1971 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Clippings (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Research (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - McCloskey family (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - 1901-1963 (Box 9, Folder 12)
      - , n.d., 1964-1971 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Research and notes (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Some McCloskey family records (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Mitchell family (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, n.d., 1924-1970 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Notes and documents, (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 17-18)
    - Mitchell, R., b. 1811 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Noe family (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Pipes family (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence, 1950-1971 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - The Descendants of John Pipes, Jr. (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Notes and documents (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Shipley family (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, 1933-1971 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Shipley and Mitchell families--miscellaneous notes (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Shipley, Mitchell, and Thompson families (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Published text (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Stearman family (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Stith (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Stone family (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Thompson family (Box 9, Folder 30)
    (James, John, Stephen, Stith, Virginia)
    - James Thompson, b. 1790 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - John Thompson, b. 1775, (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 32-33)
    - Stith Thompson, d. 1796 (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Stephen Thompson, d. 1836 (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - Virginia Thompsons (Box 9, Folder 35)